DEAR VIEWERS, WELCOME TO THIS
SCREENING OF CAUGHT IN THE NET.
THIS VERSION OF THE FILM IS INTENDED
FOR VIEWERS AGED 15 AND OVER.
Parents of 60% of Czech children
do not limit their
Internet access time.
41% of children confirm
that they received pornographic
picture from someone.
Half of the children
chats with strangers.
Every fifth child
would agree to a personal meeting.
Documentary film of
Barbora Chalupova and Vít Klusák
Caught in the Net
Documentary filmmakers
are looking for an adult actress,
looking 12-13 years old.
They have asked to come dressed
as teenagers to the casting.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
Come sit down.
This is Bára Chalupová, I'm Vít Klusák
and we're directing this documentary.
Just as we'll decide if we want you,
you also have the option
of deciding if you want in,
because it's a tricky area.
We're working on a documentary about
the abuse of children online.
That's why we're looking for a
young-looking adult woman.
If we choose you, you'd act
like you were 12.
We'd use your childhood photos
to create a profile
where you would communicate with
men who would contact you.
The question is whether you
wouldn't find it too upsetting.
I have personal
experience with this.
When I was 12 I also went
on these websites.
We chatted and he started sending
me nude photos of himself.
I was 12 or 13 and was
going through puberty
and wouldn't discuss stuff
like that with my parents.
When I was about 14 some man wrote
asking for some photos of me.
He was able to mess with kids'
heads and did it to me too.
He pretended to be a friend but he
wasn't. That was the worst thing.
He claimed to be
three years older than me
and I liked the idea of an older
boy being interested in me.
But then he sent some photos
and he was pretty old.
We chatted about my interests.
He said he had some pets and asked
if I'd like to see them
and what kinds of animals I liked.
Then we skyped. He said his camera
was broken and never showed himself.
But he wanted me to wear a light top
and a short skirt, and I did it.
He used some programme
to get into my webcam.
I had my notebook open and
whenever I changed
he used it to watch me.
But I didn't know.
It's not children's fault.
I didn't understand it.
I was glad to have a friend to write to.
I only realised it was wrong
when he said he was naked in the bath
thinking about me.
This is kind of awkward, but
I started masturbating then
and he even saw that.
In the end we were meant to
meet at the Main Train Station.
If mum hadn't checked my phone that
night, who knows how it would have ended.
Some guy wrote to me
saying he needed my virgin urine.
He said it'd really help him
and that he would pay me.
He said what would really help would be
if the urine was warm,
if I could pee right there.
It came out he was 45
and abused girls in that way.
He had lots of videos at home with all
kinds of stuff and sold them abroad.
Two years later some
guy sent photos of me,
saying if I didn't send him
something he'd make them public.
To this day I'm afraid something
will turn up somewhere.
Because of it I saw
a psychologist for two years.
- Thanks a lot.
- Thank you. Goodbye.
Bye.
Goodbye.
Out of 23 participants in the casting
19 met in childhood
with some form of online harassment.
THREE ACTRESSES
THREE CHILDREN'S ROOMS
TEN DAYS
ONLINE FROM 12.00 TO MIDNIGHT
- Can we take these drawings?
- They're not from my childhood.
- They fit the story symbolically.
- OK, sure.
- And the cat too?
- That's a fox!
They're my drawings. I never used
to draw - I'm useless at it.
I preferred to read.
Which reminds me, I've
prepared these books,
classics like Twilight
and Vampire Academy.
- And definitely sheet music
- I played the piano a lot.
I got my mum to send me a parcel
with all my sheet music.
I got that from mum for my birthday and
my prize possessions are in it:
stuff I've collected and
letters from Honza.
We've been going out for ages and
used to write each other at first.
There's also this little box he
gave me with a ring inside.
The most important thing is this
little house my dad carved.
It was like my safe where I
hid goodies
I didn't want my brother to
eat. But he did anyway.
I also had a diary, where
I recorded my problems.
You wrote about God,
but you spelt it "Gud".
- You wrote that God probably didn't exist
- otherwise he'd help you more.
I wrote that my breasts weren't growing,
which really troubled me.
- Where was the house?
- I brought it down from the attic.
Mum didn't agree with it
being shown in this project
because my dad made it
and I played with it
my whole childhood.
But it'll help me to return
to the role of a 12-year old girl.
This heart is from my first boyfriend.
- He won it shooting at a fair?
- Yeah.
- What about your headphones?
- Yeah. I can't live without them.
I see some medals -
we'll borrow them too.
- And photos.
- Thanks, I'll choose a few.
- That's me with my brother.
- Yes indeed.
- At dance class?
- That's right.
It's great you can dance - we
can draw on that on the shoot.
- May I take the cups?
- Sure. Here's a few dolls too.
- What dance style do you do?
- Latin American.
- I thought it was a real window.
- Me too.
It's prepared to the last detail.
I had this at home too.
I'm off to my room.
That's super cute.
- Wow, you've got a skylight.
- That's my dream.
- Is it hard?
- Yes.
- It fits just right.
- For sure. The perfect spot.
- I've got a window!
- The light here is gorgeous.
Jesus, they've got it just right.
For music, I'll put pop, OK?
Dance music...
She plays piano, so put
classical music too.
"I play the piano
and adore Lady Gaga."
- Lovely.
- Oh my God!
We've got 16 messages
since I set it up.
Fucking hell.
Tereza, come here.
We've set up a profile for
you on lide.cz.
You've got one profile pic
and 16 people have sent you...
It's been active only 5 minutes.
And this is?
Here I was 12 but my brother
stole one of the candles.
"My dumb bro stole the 2 from my cake,
idiot."
By your computers you've all got mobiles
with a camera for selfies.
We've found that when we
have a fake profile
and there's no communication
with a close female friend
it seems less authentic.
Tongues too.
- Did you see me?
- We can both be in it.
Niki dot Komárková, at sign...
If anyone asks you're Kristýna Jùnová.
- Your birthday...
- In November, right?
- May 20th.
- I'm a Taurus!
Careful or they'll bombard you with
spam. He's calling already. Christ.
We have our first call!
- Some Indian.
- Right. - Bára!
- We had our first call
- some Indian guy.
- When?
- Just now.
Because we were taking photos we had
Messenger on and this guy rang us.
Nader.
PROJECT RULES
1. We do not initiate chat ourselves,
we just answer.
2. At the beginning of the conversation,
note that we are 12 years old.
3. Do not flirt. Do not attract.
Do not provoke.
4. We respond to sexual suggestions
naively: "I don't know", "I'm ashamed".
5. We respond to requests to send naked
photos only after repeatedly insisting.
6. Meeting always
initiated by the molester.
7. We consult a psychologist,
sexologist, lawyer and criminologist.
8. We use Facebook, Skype,
Snapchat and Omegle.
So try it.
Oh my God.
"Hi, my name is Pavel. Let's chat."
"Man from south Moravia,
around 50."
- Bloody granddad.
- Gross.
- Seriously? - They're ancient.
- Why would he write to a girl of 13?
"Hi, you're pretty and sweet."
He just looks like a weirdo.
What about this one?
"Hi, fancy a chat?"
How old is he, 13?
That one? I can never tell with boys.
- Thirteen, 14?
- No way. Maybe 10.
I don't want to deal with this one,
but...
"Fancy chatting?"
It's nuts. Like if my granddad
wrote and said
"Hi, fancy chatting?"
But hats off he knows
how to use internet.
Fair point.
- "Ever had sex with a boy?"
- What the hell?
- Do you get it?
- He's got mushrooms.
Gardening, mushroom picking, fishing.
What's that? Marijuana? No...
Be a bit vague, like our
code of conduct says.
OK.
- "The boys in class are dumb."
- "Do they want to fuck you?"
"They want their knob in your cunt." Too
extreme. A girl of 12 wouldn't reply.
If you were contacted like this
which ones would you respond to?
I can imagine that at 12, just out
of curiosity,
I'd really like to poke
into this hornet's nest,
just to see what happens.
- To see how far you can go?
- Yeah, to find out what he's after.
Maybe to provoke him a bit, but not
like sending him nude photos.
But a girl of 12 isn't dumb. She
knows when a boy's got a hard-on.
So you might click on a profile even
knowing that's what they're after?
Yeah, but definitely not with the aim
of having a video chat and
masturbating together.
To me it's nuts they'd
expect a girl to do that.
It just struck me... did we
even enter a chat room?
No.
They approached us just
because we're online.
- As new faces.
- Gross.
- Bára, are you listening in?
- Yeah.
Right.
Stay strong.
Are we ready?
Cameras rolling. Sound rolling.
Let's do this.
Careful, don't touch your mic.
- Hi.
- What's up?
- How are you?
Fine, and you?
I'm good. I'm home alone,
which is cool.
- What are you up to?
- Just chatting.
I'm waiting for mum to get home -
then I have to go straight to bed.
You can't waste time
when you're home alone.
Where are you?
Right now I'm at the toilet.
- I'm on holidays.
- Who with?
- With my mates.
- Your mates?
"User P____ F____ took a picture."
Don't take photos of me!
I thought we'd chat.
Tomorrow, OK?
"How would you rate
the quality of this conversation?"
That's a dick.
That's really gross!
Really gross!
Come and join us.
It's remarkable how they have zero
interest in the impact of what they do.
It's the utilitarian
use of that child.
It's sexuality devoid of any feeling.
I need to come, that's what you're
here for, then Seeya?
That's awful. I just don't know...
But that's not how it is in most cases.
I know. I'm in a pretty
decent relationship.
But if those young girls
are exposed to this
what kind of mindset will they
have when it comes to a relationship?
They're definitely shocked.
- It also establishes a norm...
- Which can be highly distorted.
when it comes to how it will
be with men later.
Hi.
Do you think it's dumb
you can't see me?
I'm a bit afraid.
I've no idea who I'm talking to.
I see. I don't show my face
much on the web.
What grade are you in?
Seventh.
You... put your hand under the table.
- Yeah.
- But why?
Why not? Do you mind?
- Yeah.
- I won't do it then.
You never did anything like that?
I've never done anything,
so I don't know what it's like.
Actually me neither.
You've never done it either?
Some stuff yeah, but I've
never fully done it.
It? What's "it"?
Sex. Like all the way.
Maybe that's why
I'm here online
trying to find some other ways.
Maybe you could find a girlfriend,
or at least try to.
Maybe it's not as hard as it seems.
It's already a bit weird. I'm
a little older than you.
Other boys have done it
but for me still nothing.
Still, I hope you find a girlfriend.
I think it's better to have a real
girl than over the internet.
Jesus.
- Good afternoon.
- Hiya.
- What will we chat about?
- Whatever you like.
Yeah? How old are you actually?
Around 12?
- OK. You're pretty.
- How old are you?
- Forty-five. Is that a lot?
- I guess not.
- Already in your pyjamas?
- No.
Do you fancy me even a bit?
- Want to see it?
- See what?
My penis.
Ever seen one before?
- Yeah, but only on the internet.
- Yeah?
- Have you ever watched porn?
- Yeah, with a friend.
I'll take my t-shirt off.
You don't feel hot anymore?
Hot? No, I feel good.
Hang on, I'll take my trousers off.
It's starting to get hard.
- I see. Why?
- You turn me on.
I'll take my boxers off too.
Come on, I'll show it to you.
- Can you see my big belly?
- Yeah.
But you don't find it too pleasant,
do you? Say something.
I've got you back on my monitor.
At least show me your breasts.
Don't worry. I'm far away -
I can't do a thing to you.
Does your mum know?
- That you're showing me your penis?
- Yeah.
No way. I'd be in big trouble.
That's my point.
On TV they often say that
young girls visit chat rooms
and I know parents worry.
On one hand it's right
they keep tabs on kids,
but on the other they limit you a bit.
So which side is right?
- Would you like to get together?
- I guess not.
You'd prefer a younger guy?
I guess I can hold
off on boys for a bit.
- For sure.
- Yeah.
At 12 you're just starting to develop.
You're a young rosebud.
I'm getting cold.
I'll put my shirt on.
Good idea.
I guess I'll go to bed.
Yeah?
- Take care then.
- Bye.
It doesn't matter that I'm 12?
Not if it stays our secret.
- You really don't mind that I'm 12?
- I'm trying not to think about it.
- You don't mind me being 12?
- Why should I,
when we fancy each other?
Who cares. I was 12 once too.
You are young. But if you don't mind...
You do know I'm 12?
You don't mind?
- No. Will you show yourself to me too?
- I don't think so. Sorry.
- Why not?
- I'm really shy.
Try it. If you help me,
I'll jizz for you.
These men often wrongly think
that when the girl doesn't actively
resist, she must want it.
They forget that it's totally natural
for a person to behave a bit submissively
when they encounter someone above them
who is bigger physically, with
a deep voice, older.
The consent is illusory.
If the girl didn't feel pressured,
she would never agree to it.
Many people think they're pedophiles,
but that's not the case.
In pedophilia it's not so much about
looking at photos of naked children.
It's about being in
their children's world,
communicating with them -
that's the attraction.
Even the research says
that there's only 3-5% of pedofiles
among those who chase
children on the internet.
This one is online...
Jan Nováèek junior.
- I'm curious who Jan Nováèek senior is?
- His dad I guess.
- "You're really pretty..."
- "Thanks."
- "Man from Ústí region, 30"
- God, he's gross.
"What are you wearing?"
"Hairy socks."
I'm not sure about the spelling.
- "Any hair down there yet?"
- He's asking about your crotch, right?
- "I'm embarrassed!!!"
- "Don't be shy. You're pretty."
- "Have you had sex?"
- "I'm just 12."
- "Do you stroke your pussy?"
- "Why?"
"Look at my profile."
But it's public! Christ!
How should I respond?
"Why do you do it?"
Bára is our make-up artist.
She says she maybe knows one of
these guys personally.
If it's really him, and both
the photo and the region fit,
then it's a man who works with kids and
runs children's camps.
He comes into contact
with a lot of kids.
He's only got one photo here,
so it may be stolen.
It might not be him.
But if it is, that's a problem.
If he worked with kids
and it is him
we just can't keep it to ourselves.
Here I go.
- Hi.
Is it him?
- Will you take your t-shirt off?
- What?
Will you take your t-shirt off?
- I don't think so.
- Come on.
No, I'm a bit shy.
You have no reason to be.
- Can you stand up for a moment?
- Why?
I want to see how you look overall.
I look normal.
What's your name?
- Martin. And yours?
- Míša. - Nice name.
Is it Martin? Did he give his real name?
He's suddenly so sleazy.
- And what else do you do?
- I go to school, chat...
- How about you?
- I have a small travel agency.
- Like excursions?
- Yeah, a travel agency.
- Is your mum home?
- No, she's at work.
That's great.
- I want to see you without the t-shirt.
- Doesn't it matter that I'm 12?
- No. Does it matter to you?
- Maybe... I don't know.
There you go.
- Will you take it off?
- What?
- Your t-shirt.
- No.
- Just for a bit.
- But I want to talk.
We can talk without the t-shirt.
Don't be shy. Just for a bit.
Then your bum. That isn't visible.
- Yeah?
- No.
- Show me what's on your shirt.
- A horse.
- Take it off.
- No.
Where are you?
- What?
- Are you at home, or where?
In a room. It's my bedroom
and office in one.
I've got a living room,
but I'm not there.
- I'll show it to you.
- All right.
- Can you see it?
- Yeah.
- Show me around your room.
- OK.
Here is my bed.
I drew this myself with a friend.
Can you see it?
Yeah. Nice.
Here I've got my stuff, my sheet music.
And a window, a piano
and a huge mess.
- Nice room.
- Thanks.
You saw my place.
- So we're even.
- I've got to go. Take care.
- Will you show me more of it?
- No, I've got to go.
- See you.
- Bye, sweetie.
- Your mic is lit up.
- Ah!
He didn't notice. We'll tape over it
and then we can continue.
- So it's him?
- It's him.
The job description fits,
everything does.
What does he actually do?
He organises camps, ski trips,
children's events.
- You can't be serious!
- Compared to yesterday's chat
that was far tougher, even though
he didn't masturbate in front of me.
But I felt like...
I'm not dumb, I know why he wanted
me to walk around the room, but...
Get set! Let's go!
Cameras rolling?
If you can't take photos,
take your t-shirt off.
No, I'm really embarrassed.
I'm not pretty.
Are you taking photos of me?
- Yeah. - Why?
- You're gorgeous. Turn around.
- Turn round.
- Which way?
Turn the other way.
Your whole body
- Why?
- Turn round completely.
- Now take your t-shirt off.
- No!
Stand up in a way
your face can't be seen.
- Why?
- I want to see how pretty you are.
I'd rather play the piano for you.
- So play.
- All right. What?
- Perhaps a bit of Bach.
- Bach? OK.
- You've got a lovely bum too.
- No!
- Yes.
- I don't.
- That's one I know.
- You're really good.
You've got a lovely smile.
- You're really pretty.
- No.
Don't be shy, sweetie.
I'll look forward to the photo.
- What?
- I look forward to the photo.
- What photo?
- You know, a photo of you.
All right, sweetie.
We'll keep in touch, OK?
- Bye.
- See you.
Thank you. Switch, please.
Hold that pose... a little longer...
Last one. Thanks. Switch, please.
I'd do a smile, but forced,
like we rehearsed it.
Each girl has around four
nude photographs.
They're not their bodies
but photomontages.
We'll send them to 30 or 40 men and
see if they try using them against us.
Do kids really send them voluntarily?
Seemingly voluntarily -
they're still teens
who mightn't be able to think through
the consequences and vulnerability
that could follow.
Why do they send these pics?
It may be so as not to lose contact
with someone who's chatting to them.
That can be very important for
the girl, particularly at an age
when teenage disagreements
with parents may start.
And here's someone who
fills that need for them.
It often happens they regret it at
once but by then the blackmail starts.
Like "I'll tell your friend,
everyone will know.
We'll say it at your school
and to your mum."
Some kids can't imagine
confessing the truth
and see ending their lives
as the only solution.
That's easier than telling their
parents what's happened.
"Hi"
You're not going to speak?
"What will you show me?"
I don't know.
"Stand up and
take your sweatshirt off."
"Take your t-shirt off."
"I'm horny."
I see.
I'm super interested in what you
wrote about your perversions.
"Quite a few, eh?"
It's really weird.
"It's different, that's why I like it."
What was it you wrote about dogs?
"I have a friend, a girl, who does it."
- Really?
- "I don't, I just watch."
"Yes."
- "I'll send you the videos."
- OK then.
"I want you to undress."
Isn't it abuse of animals?
"They like it, otherwise they
wouldn't do it."
"I'm starting to be annoyed. You said
you'd show me whatever I want."
But you said you'd give me
500 crowns a week.
How much would you give me
just for stripping?
"It's 500 a week for pics, messages
and showing yourself naked."
Are you jerking off?
"Yeah."
"Let's wrap it up. Seems like
you're not up for it."
Up for what?
- He really sent a dog!
- Don't press play.
Anyone got anything else?
I've got four.
Have you got anyone, Sabina?
- Yeah, loads.
- OK, now we're with you.
Holy shit.
She has 900 Facebook requests.
- So call him.
- Ready? - Yeah.
"Interested in making money?"
"Making money how?"
I'm calling him.
Hi.
- What are you up to?
- I just got home from school.
What's new?
Nothing, I guess.
- And with you?
- Nothing.
So you're interested in the money?
It's up to you.
I'm not forcing you into anything.
How would it work with the money?
I'll pop it into an envelope, you
give me the address and I'll post it.
Then you accept delivery. Easy.
And what for?
Showing yourself to me
and doing as I say.
What would I have to do?
Show me your breasts, properly,
then strip down below -
and then we'll see.
How much would you give me?
Depends on the stuff you do.
So how much?
If you do what I want, 2,000 crowns.
Will you show me the
money on camera?
One sec, I'll see how much
I have on me.
And it's worth that much money to you?
You're pretty. I like how you look.
Why don't you just watch porn?
I'm not so into porn.
I prefer it live like this.
- You'd really send me money?
- Yeah.
Though I don't know how.
By post maybe.
- Every week?
- Yeah.
But you said...
"User Sneeky took a picture"
that girls who sleep with
boys for money are...
...that they're whores.
- That's really rude.
- No, it isn't.
You wrote you'd send me 500
crowns a week?
Yeah.
- What for exactly?
- We'll agree on that.
Will we?
Yeah. I've got to go change
some wheels.
- Ok, see you.
- Later.
- Hi.
You're not shy, eh?
- How old are you?
- 43.
- You really don't mind me being 12?
- No.
When I was 35 I had a
girlfriend of 13.
- Nobody could do a thing about it.
- Honestly? - Yeah.
- And you also did... it together?
- Yeah. That too.
- Everything?
- Everything.
Then she ran away and came
to live with me.
She hid at my place for a one month.
They looked for her everywhere.
Then her mum said she and the dad
had accepted it and wouldn't stop her.
- How is it going out with someone young?
- Normal.
Today most 13-year olds are as mature as
if they were 25.
Why aren't you still together?
She started losing weight fast so we
went to the doctor and she had cancer.
A year later she died.
Tell me something about yourself.
Forget the past,
now I'm interested in you.
What's most beautiful for a
girl is a romantic day
when the guy is experienced
and drives you wild and next
thing you're not a virgin.
If I knew we'd meet, I
wouldn't have left Plzeò.
- Where do you live now?
- Far away.
In England.
Boo.
You wouldn't fancy England?
- Lots.
- You'd like it? Yeah?
Will you come see me?
If we get to know each other well,
I'll find a school for you -
so we can be together.
No?
- What do you like doing...
- Sorry, mum's coming.
I'm off to England. To study.
I want you to send me a photo,
but a nice one.
Like the one you sent me
with the cushion -
one like that, but with your face.
A cute snap, maybe when you're in bed.
- One like that, OK?
- Just the face, or...?
A normal one, with you
under the quilt, say.
- But I've got no breasts.
- Don't say that. They're nice.
- Just for a sec. - What for a sec?
- I want to see your breasts.
- Please, not now.
- Sweetie...
Don't cry.
- Not now.
- OK, I didn't say a thing.
Don't cry. If you do,
I'll look the other way.
You're beautiful. Don't be sad.
- Can you see me now?
- Yeah.
Get up.
I can't see anything.
- Will you take off your pyjama top?
- What?
- Take it off.
- No. No way.
Will you take me a photo?
I've never tried it.
Go to the bathroom, take off
your top and take me a selfie.
- Is that your room?
- It is, yeah.
Will you show it to me?
This is my bed, wardrobe
and I've got a little rabbit.
Here he is.
Nice.
Will you send a daring photo?
- A photo? I'm not sure
- Of your breasts, maybe.
- I'm not sure
- Will you?
I'll send you something too.
Bye for now. You're so pretty.
Bloody hell, this is really hard.
Show me your breasts, baby.
What? My breasts? No.
It'll hurt me. Please, ease my pain.
It hurts. Come on now.
What do you mean, it'll hurt?
Semen returns to the man's body
and then it hurts.
Just show me your breasts
so I can come.
- You're not Czech?
- I'm half-Czech.
- It really hurts?
- Awfully. It's the same for every guy.
I never knew guys suffered.
You don't have a dick, so
how would you know?
You're so pretty. I want you.
I expect we'll get together.
So show me your breasts
already - help me!
I don't want to hurt you.
But if you don't show me your breasts
and it hurts real bad, I'll probably
end up in hospital tomorrow.
Because of me?
I guess so.
What would they do to you
at the hospital?
I don't know.
Maybe you need...
Please, I want to come already. Let's
leave the chat for later.
Will you be angry with me
if I don't do it?
I will.
"Your pic will be online. In school.
Your mum'll see it."
No fucking way!
- "I'll do it because you're nasty."
- Now he's using blackmail!
Are you going to post
that pic somewhere?
I didn't want to send it.
You wrote you wouldn't show it to
anybody, that you're no asshole.
And now you say it's going
on the internet?
- But why?
- You're nasty.
Why?
You like to hurt people.
You hurt people.
Absolutely untrue.
- You promised to show me your breasts.
- I did not.
I just said we'd swap pics.
Mum will murder me.
Lift your t-shirt up.
- Just show me your breasts.
- No way!
- Yes, you will.
- I'll erase the photo.
It's already in my archive.
So show them to me.
- Hi.
- Hi there.
- How old are you?
- Guess.
- About 30.
- I'm 26.
What about me?
You're 12 or 13.
Twelve.
- Are you a student?
- Not any more. I work in Brno.
- What did you study?
- Engineering. At university.
Do you often chat with people?
Just with guys who want to chat.
- Just chatting?
- Well, you know...
Some are interested in something else.
Such as?
I'd rather not say.
Do you think it's the same,
making love like this
and in reality?
- It's different.
- What's the difference?
You don't touch the other person,
but you have your imagination.
- But you've already made love?
- Yeah.
Maybe you could show me something,
just a little.
- Please.
- I'm even shy with myself.
If you showed me something,
it'd help me.
And what would help me?
I'd tell you how to use your
fingers, stuff like that.
- Does that turn you on?
- Yeah.
Even though I'm 12?
As I said, I don't mind.
Oh man. Fucking hell.
- Hi.
When you said you watch porn...
Yeah.
what sites do you use?
For example, x_____.com
And you watch girls as young as me?
Hardly ever. Sometimes.
That stuff exists?
I use one site with videos like that.
You're not allowed to download it
but there are sites with that stuff.
Get her to ask, What does
a girl need to become a woman?
I can send you a video - not
of sex, just what's on there.
Not to scare you by sending sex
right off,
I'll send one young video
so you can see what's there.
What must a girl have to
become a woman?
I'm not sure what she needs.
It's more about behaviour.
Do you think I behave like a woman?
You behave nicely.
OK, I guess I'll send it...
Send it by Skype. I'll send you one too.
- OK.
- Bye, my love.
What did he say?
- What's that?
- What did you...?
Can you play that video?
What is it?
- Jesus, she must be 10.
- She's got no breasts at all.
- That's a vibrator.
- She's a little girl. - Super young.
- Can you please stop it?
- I'm trying.
When I see what you're doing
and who you're communicating with,
it's a real torrent of every
illegal act and crime
against children one can imagine.
I counted at least eight.
All these predators you unfortunately
have to communicate with
deserve to be jailed.
These are very serious crimes,
including rape and blackmail
endangering the upbringing of children,
inciting immorality,
sexual abuse other than
through intercourse.
These are all forms of base behaviour,
masturbation, etc. -
basically everything you've seen,
and much more besides.
What I've seen here is the lowest
filth I've ever come across.
Given the number of such people online,
can anything really be done about it?
This is the consequence, but what's
very important is blocking it.
I'm surprised that providers
of such services
don't filter or control this
communication in any way.
They should administer their sites and
if they discover this is happening
they should clearly take action.
But that would force down
user numbers
and of course they get rich from ads.
That'd be a disaster for them, so they
create a space where this can happen.
So I'm calling.
Get set.
Nobody wants me!
They do want me!
- Calm down, Tereza.
- Sorry, I'm doing my best.
- It's someone else, right?
- It doesn't matter.
- Hi.
- Can you hear me?
- Sure.
- Can you see me too? - Yeah.
- I can't see you.
- One sec.
Hi.
Good afternoon.
How are you? The weekend's
coming, so that's cool.
- Some free time.
- Yeah.
- How old are you?
- How old do you think?
About 70.
Not yet, thank God.
- I'm 12. Is that OK?
- That's cool.
So you're like 60?
Fifty.
- My granddad's 50 too.
- Yeah?
- Do you have grandkids?
- Yeah.
I do.
How old are they?
Twenty and 22.
- Is the grandmother around?
- She is.
Don't you love her anymore?
I do.
Why?
Well, you're calling me.
So what? We're just chatting.
That's true.
How about you?
Got any suitors?
Loads!
You're not sad then.
- Mainly online.
- Yeah, that's possible these days.
Do you play with the boys too?
You don't have a prince charming
you can snuggle up with?
No.
What are you doing there?
Nothing. I was just polishing something.
"Just polishing"!
Hey, the guy who sent me the porn
with the dog and the girl
is now threatening he'll post
my photos online.
If I don't reply, he'll post them
and my mum won't be happy.
Let's call him.
Hey, one second, I've got something.
- Looks like he did post the photos.
- Show us.
- Jesus Christ.
- We've got a new profile.
Show us. Your face is visible too.
It must be unbelievable when a girl
sees her pics have been posted.
My nude photos are all over lide.cz.
"Are you going to behave right, then?
Otherwise they're staying up. Got it?"
"Should I leave them up?
It was your choice. Seeya."
"If you can't even say Hi I'll
post them elsewhere."
"You're making it worse, not replying.
What will your folks say?"
Fucking hell, if I was 12
I'd jump off a bridge.
- Can you report it?
- I don't know how.
- It must be possible.
- So help me find it here.
- Hi.
Have you got a webcam?
One sec, I'm trying to turn it on.
- How old are you?
- Guess.
About 30?
Twenty. I'm 20.
- Are you a student?
- Yeah, third level.
Thank God, I wouldn't fancy working yet.
- Where do you study?
- I'm at nursing college.
What a choice - it's super difficult.
- Do you have a girlfriend?
- Yeah.
Why isn't she with you?
I still live with my
folks and so does she.
Why are you chatting to me?
I like chatting to anybody with a brain
and you don't seem dumb, so it's cool.
Thanks.
You know, one guy offered me
money to strip.
- Not a good idea.
- Why not?
Simple. If you did it, it could be all
over the place. Not nice.
But I've got a nice body.
Cool, liking yourself is the
first step to success but
it's your privacy, so only someone you
love should see it.
Not some stranger who wouldn't
give a damn about you.
I don't know what I'd do
if that happened.
I do. You'd cry and your mum
and dad would be pissed off.
Then you'd have to find out
which asshole did it.
You're not the only one boys have
tried it on with. A few were into me.
Hilarious.
They were also touching themselves,
you know, between their legs.
I'd have helped them get off too,
but I'd need a chainsaw
or big boots to make sure they never
did it again, because it's wrong.
I took the piss out of a girl who
promised to show me everything.
I said, Seriously? Show me your brain -
cut your skull open and just take it out.
She blocked me right away.
If she says she'll show everything
why not the brain too?
Evidently there wasn't one.
Most interesting.
Did she send you pics?
No. I would've just deleted them anyway.
What is she to me?
Doesn't it turn you on?
No. If I want to get turned on
I've got a girlfriend,
or there's billions of porn sites where
I can find what I like
and I don't need some girl I don't know.
I find you quite attractive.
I try to look good, though I've just
got out of the bath,
which feels good after being
on my feet all day.
What?
You hardly know me.
If you say you do, I'll ask you something
and there's no way you'll know it.
Ask away.
What colour are your eyes?
They look black.
Brown.
Brown?
Let's see. You're shy, sincere,
a trier, on the quiet side.
What's wrong?
- What is it?
- Nothing.
So your eyes are just sweating?
Or they're bored?
- Can I call you back in a bit?
- Sure. But what's up?
- Later.
- Bye.
I need a tissue.
Bloody hell.
That was really touching. Sorry.
What a nice boy.
- He's so nice.
- One of the good guys.
After these 10 days I'm moved when
I come across somebody decent.
I'm curious how these guys who've
contacted us will react
when we disappear from this world.
Will they be left with some feeling?
Will we have some impact on them?
After our chats, did they say to
themselves, Christ, she was only 12?
Suddenly we'll be gone and maybe
some of them will miss us.
I really hope they're left with some
kind of feeling, even though I doubt it.
It'll be so great to see you in person.
I'll be nice to you. Don't you worry.
When could we meet in person?
I could arrange a weekend at a cottage
in January. I'd buy you nice underwear.
Anything you want.
We can meet up when you're in Prague.
You can play the piano and meet my cat.
We could meet sometime.
- You'd want to?
- Yeah. - For real?
- Would you like to?
- I don't know. What would we do?
I'd take you to a cake shop
for a cocoa.
Maybe some cake too.
- If you eat cake, that is?
- I love cake.
If we just place this here like so.
The last switch - the last one.
This is a wireless earpiece.
Put it in your ear.
Hello Sabinka. Can we hear each other?
Yeah, I can hear you Bára.
If it gets uncomfortable, just say.
- Just so you don't feel sick.
- It's fine.
Really get him talking.
Bring up again the stuff that seemed
important during the chat.
- Is the sound OK?
- Rolling.
Camera rolling.
BODYGUARD
He's here.
- Hi.
- Hi there.
- I'm Ivan.
- And I'm Markéta.
- A little surprise for you.
- What a journey.
Yeah?
- Hi.
- It's my first time here.
I'm Týnka.
So will you explain it to me?
It's dangerous to talk about it.
- Who would hear us?
- You never know.
How much older are you?
- Half a century!
- Fifty years?
I've got no wife or kids.
I can do what I want. So...
I thought it might be a problem
that I haven't turned 15 yet.
- Or do you think it doesn't matter?
- It doesn't matter.
You really don't mind that I'm just 12?
You already asked that.
I know but it still feels
weird that like...
- Like what?
- Maybe you wouldn't like me.
If I wasn't into you,
I wouldn't be here.
It's like this. You've got
to decide what you want.
I'm telling you straight - I won't
pressure you into anything
or talk you into anything.
If you're into it, we can meet more
often. You can get to know me better.
We can go for walks, maybe go
to Žižkov TV tower.
Or get a hot chocolate somewhere.
- What have you brought me? You said you would.
- Chocolate.
- Lots of chocolate.
- What kind?
Strawberry, yoghurt-flavoured,
with nuts, white chocolate.
- What's up?
- Nothing. - Are you nervous?
Big-time.
The girl with the dog you sent
me was pretty gross.
Really gross.
You really watch that stuff?
- What's the attraction?
- It's different. - Different?
It's not the same old same old.
I thought lovemaking should
be out of love.
You're still young.
Today's world is sick.
You'll realise when you're older.
Yeah?
What about girls?
Nothing. I'm writing to you right now.
I'm on the lookout, but so far
I've had no luck finding...
The right girl?
- So explain it to me.
- What we're going to do?
We'll get there, check in.
I'll take a shower.
Then what?
Then you can join me.
You can touch it and play with it.
I'll show you how to play with yourself.
- I'll show you how much there is.
- How much what?
That stuff when it...
- When what?
- When I come.
I'll enter, in a towel.
I'll lie down on my stomach.
You'll take some oil and drip it on me.
I'll say, Oh, that's cold.
Then you'll start to spread it.
On my back and arms.
Legs, thighs, bum, whatever -
it's up to you.
Have you ever had an orgasm?
No.
- So we'll fix that.
- I'm not sure what it is.
I'd touch your clitoris.
I'd massage it.
What exactly is the 'clirotis'?
- Clitoris.
- Clitoris, then.
It's a little lump.
- A lump?
- Above the vagina.
- Above the what?
- The vagina. The pussy.
- I thought a lump was some disease.
- No.
- Our dog had a lump and it died.
- Depends what kind of a lump.
- I don't have any lump.
- I reckon you do.
Definitely not.
We can check later.
This is what you have.
It's an enlarged image of
something small you have.
- I've got this?
- Yes.
No way. It's ugly.
You've got something
similar... between...
You've definitely got it.
Could you, like, explain it to me?
- Explain what?
- What exactly is a threesome?
You tell her.
She'll like...
She'll do what?
Basically you lick me down below
and then you fuck him.
That's the basic idea.
- You don't mind that I'm 12?
- No.
The thing is, I'm still a virgin.
I've never slept with anyone.
- It's no big deal.
- It's fine.
Are you menstruating yet?
Just a few times and not so much.
Not regular, like.
That'll come when you're 14 or 15.
I only had them regularly from 15.
Above all I don't want you
showing my mum nude photos of me.
So I should put this in my account?
Give it back to me for a minute.
I'm giving you this so that you never
send those photos anywhere.
OK.
But how can I trust you
to never do it?
You keep saying you'll post them
somewhere, send them to my mum,
that you'll get homeless
guys to fuck me.
Why not say it a bit louder
so everybody can hear.
Could I ask, for my own peace of mind,
to erase the messages
we exchanged?
No problem.
You mean the one with the cream?
Start from the bottom.
Here maybe:
"You can make me come using your
mouth, give me a nice blow job."
Don't read it out here.
When you say you want to jizz
inside me - that too?
- How do you do it?
- "Delete".
And also "Would you mind if
you got pregnant"?
- "You don't mind that I've got a big one?"
- Delete that too.
Hang on. What's this?
This is... for example, like...
So I don't need to feel embarrassed.
Why not delete everything?
Why only some? I'll just delete all.
- Yeah, and then we can start writing again.
- Fine.
I'm not here.
Dad. Hi.
Dad, you don't need to come here.
Just wait there. Don't go anywhere.
Are you in the area?
- I'll go pay.
- Good idea.
Seeya.
I'm off.
That's a pity.
Bye.
For three months you want
me to send you gross stuff.
Keep it down.
I don't give a shit who hears.
- I do.
- That's your problem.
Cool it.
So it's OK to send a girl of 12 pics
of someone fucking a dog?
That you write that you're a
pedophile pig?
That you say you want to rape me anally
and fuck me in a car? That's OK to you?
- Do you feel good about yourself?
- No.
- Do you think your life is cool?
- So why do you do it?
- I don't know. - Wait a sec.
Thank you.
I can't change that now.
I apologise - accept it or not.
I can't accept your apology
when you're a total pig!
You posted photos of
a girl of 12 online,
blackmailed her and were gross to her.
Oh well.
Who by violence
or by use of threats
forces a child
under the age of 15
for masturbation,
or exposing oneself,
is punishable by imprisonment
from 5 to 12 years.
Shh, you'll betray us.
- Good evening. Are you Martin _______?
- No, I'm not.
I'm Vít Klusák, this is Bára Chalupová.
We're making a documentary about
the online abuse of children.
What do you want from me?
You sent photos to our actresses.
What law did I break?
It's illegal to send
porn links to minors.
I've never done that.
- I can send them back to you.
- Then you'd be doing the same thing.
You can't expose yourself or tell
a girl of 12 how to masturbate.
And you've run camps for kids.
You contact girls in large numbers.
I've never met up with anyone,
never molested a child.
You expose yourself over Skype.
- How do you know it's me?
- We've recorded your face, your penis.
We know your green walls. We know you.
- Why do you do it?
- Do what?
Why send your penis to girls of 12?
I have to go the back way.
Come if you like?
- If you'll speak, why make us chase you?
- OK, give me a question.
Go ahead.
You work with kids. Do you think it's OK
to send what you do to young girls?
I can send what I like.
Unless I send them a link to porn,
which I haven't.
You did. Our whole crew saw it.
- A porn link?
- Yes, to child porn.
"Here are girls like you" -
you sent me that.
It's totally gross.
Maybe I sent one accidentally.
But that's irrelevant.
What's the point of what you're doing?
Guess how many men contacted
them in a week.
- A thousand.
- Exactly.
And you're surprised?
Why not do something worthwhile?
I was in those girls' shoes three months
and I still have nightmares.
Do you think I care what you or
anybody else think of me?
I don't give a damn
what you think of me.
If you had a daughter of 12
you'd see it differently.
Go down the road there and
you can buy a 12-year-old.
That's normal here. Far worse
problems aren't being addressed.
This hit TV show makes Gypsies look
great but they're all on welfare.
Why not address that?
Our film's about online child abuse.
- I find it relaxing, fun.
- Why such young girls?
Why not find someone older?
I chat with all ages.
- How old do you think these girls are?
- Fifteen.
- All fifteen?
- Yeah, maybe.
- What if they're just 14?
- It's only chat.
- What do you do for fun?
- I look after my four kids.
I wouldn't like my daughter of nine
to write to somebody like you.
It's your fault she's raised so she goes
online and chats with such types.
Why did you want photos of us?
You ordered us to strip on camera.
If you were well brought up,
you wouldn't do it.
It's the parents' fault.
You're punishing them for
a bad upbringing?
No, I'm not. I didn't raise them.
If a child doesn't tell their parents
about chatting to some man for hours,
it's their problem, not mine.
It's not my fault they haven't been
taught to tell their folks everything.
But you look after children.
I see photos of you as a camp leader.
I've never touched a child.
That's not the issue.
Maybe you affect a child's mind
when you write you adore her.
Do you know how much it can mess
with a 12-year-old's mind?
You're skilled at chatting with kids.
You're charismatic.
It doesn't occur to you that
this game is a kind of defence for me?
Against everything that's going on here.
Look around you.
You're defending yourself by
writing to minors?
Why concern yourself with such stuff?
So that you stop harming children.
During the 10 days of filming
Míše, Týnke and Niky
were attacked by 2458 men in total.
In the coming weeks
the girls took part
in 21 meetings "in real life".
The police of the Czech Republic
requested the filming of material
and criminal proceedings were initiated
on its basis.
ORIGINAL IDEA
WRITTEN AND DIRECTED BY
CINEMATOGRAPHY
EDITOR
MUSIC
SOUND
EXECUTIVE PRODUCER
HEAD OF PRODUCTION
DIGITAL MASKS DESIGNER